BLAKE LA PIERRE

blakelapierre@gmail.com \diamond github.com/blakelapierre (949) \cdot 259 \cdot 3040 \diamond Nixon, Texas

ABOUT

A software developer with direct experience at all levels of the software lifecycle, including requirements gathering, design, analysis, implementation, testing, deployment and maintainence. A rapid learner with the ability to quickly integrate an understanding of a project's goals with the project's details. Has a demonstrated ability to identify and resolve inefficiencies and flawed processes.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Languages C#, Typescript, Javascript, HTML, SQL, Java, CSS/LESS,

C/C++, Python, Ruby, XML

Protocols & APIs JSON, SOAP, REST

Databases Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Firebird Frameworks & Libraries React, Angular, ExtJS, jQuery, ASP.NET, ASP, Node.js Git, SVN, TeamCity, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Linux, Windows

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

none

Chief Principal Architect

February 2013 - Present

Connecticut; California; DC; Texas

- · Vision, research, design, prototyping, implementation, documentation, and marketing.
- · Widespread application of work and educational experience to develop software. Developed proofs-of-concepts & usable projects, contributed to open source projects, developed open source libraries.
- · Public communication and collaboration on developed software, others' software, science, software, and public interest topics.

Custom Solutions

Sole Proprietor

December 2015 - April 2016 Berkeley, California

- · Produced custom solutions to client problems.
- · Primary project was a "gamification" for insurance product sales for a client of our client.
- · Interpreted client requirements, architected and delivered entire solution, which consisted of a fully brand new PostgreSQL schema & functions, Node.js API/RPC with web server backend, and custom web front-end.

Tallan, Inc.

Consultant

November 2012 - February 2013 $Rocky\ Hill,\ Connecticut$

- · Performed deep and wide analysis of Prudential Financial, Inc.'s retirement solutions databases, including the 401 (k) and other defined contribution plans they manage.
- · Identified critical flaws in the design and content of the databases and recommended possible solutions/best practices.
- · Saved thousands of previously estimated man-hours by identifying inefficencies in current processes and subsequently designing and implementing custom analysis software to automate large parts of the analysis.
- · Contributed to a large store of data quality metrics that will be re-calculated and re-analyzed by the software as part of on going data quality measures.

Software Marketing Associates, Inc.

Senior Software Developer

September 2007 - June 2012 Rocky Hill, Connecticut

- · Led small (5-7 people) team of developers to develop next generation of web-based fulfillment business software on top of the .NET platform.
- · Designed and implemented core frameworks and libraries used across the entire software solution including: data persistence, backend web server, frontend HTML/Javascript GUI, web services, Windows services, and others.
- · Designed and developed end-user installer that performed a non-trivial installation of many heterogenous components, including numerous legacy COM+ components, IIS hosted websites, MS SQL Server databases and various services.
- · Designed, developed and deployed software and processes to automate the entire code change lifecycle, from developer commit to the change running live on a customer's machine, both for multiple yearly releases and bi-weekly update deployments.
- · Developed and deployed numerous company-wide and department-wide tools for issue tracking, work-flow automation and code generation.
- · Transitioned company from VSS source control and a manual copy-build-patch-deploy cycle to a continuous integration build cycle backed by Subversion and TeamCity.
- · Mentored and trained developers. Created and maintained a Wiki for the development team and authored other types of documentation.

Institute of Transportation Studies Developer

February 2006 - June 2007 Irvine, California

- · Designed, implemented, tested and debugged integration software written in C, C++, Visual C++, and C# to allow .NET software to interoperate with legacy C software.
- · Designed, implemented, tested and debugged software written in C# with extensive use of WinForms for visualizing data gathered from simulation software.
- · Responsible for porting legacy plugins written in C to C#.
- · Provided documentation and training to staff for software that was developed.

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine

June 2007

B.S. in Information & Computer Science

With specializations in Computer Systems & Networks and Distributed Systems

Overall GPA: 3.51/4.00